<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<knowl mode="exercise" xmlns="https://spatext.clontz.org" version="0.2">
    <intro>
    <p><em>Scenario:</em></p>
    <p>
        The US Army wants to get an idea of how Americans feel about the current conflict in Ukraine. In order to get the information, the Army partnered with Quinnipiac University to randomly send a survey to 950 Army Officers living at Fort Bragg. Survey respondents completed the survey online using a code provided in the invitation. The survey was available in English.</p>
    <p>
        Survey respondents were asked to decide to what degree they agreed with the following statements. The possible answer were "Strongly Agree", "Agree", "Neither Agree or Disagree", "Disagree", "Strongly Disagree".</p>
    
        <list>
            <item><p>Russia needs to be punished for its evil actions taken to completely destroy the lives of Ukrainian citizens.</p></item>
            <item><p>The people responsible for the US military response to the conflict are extremely cowardly not to put the extraordinary US military in the field against the Russians.</p></item>
        </list>
    <p>
        <m>{{sample}}</m> Officers responded to the survey. <m>{{result_1}}</m><m>\%</m> of respondents said that they {{agree_1}} that Russia needs to be punished for its evil actions taken to completely destroy the lives of Ukrainian citizens and <m>{{result_2}}</m><m>\%</m> said that they {{agree_2}} that the people responsible for the US military response to the conflict are extremely cowardly not to put the extraordinary US military in the field against the Russians.</p>
        
    </intro>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>Does the above use a sampling frame? If so, what is the sampling frame?</p></content>
        <outtro><p>Yes, Army Officers at Fort Bragg</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>What is the sampling method used in the above scenario?</p></content>
        <outtro><p>The sampling method was a simple random sample or SRS</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>Looking at the sampling frame and the sampling method, would the sample be a valid sample or is it likely to be a biased sample? Explain why.</p></content>
        <outtro><p>The sample frame is likely to produce a biased sample</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>Identify potential sources of bias other than the sampling method from the information given and explain why they lead to bias (Only use the information given, do not speculate about information not provided).</p></content>
        <outtro><p>The wording of the statements (it is ok if a student says only one language although all US Officers must know English).</p></outtro></knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>If the US Army did the survey again, would you expect that exactly <m>{{result_1}}</m><m>\%</m> of respondents would {{agree_1}} that Russia needs to be punished for its evil actions taken to completely destroy the lives of Ukrainian citizens? Why or why not?</p></content>
        <outtro><p>No, the exact same result would not be expected due to natural variability</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>Based on the results of this survey, can the US Army be sure they have a good idea of how Americans feel about the current conflict in Ukraine? Why or why not?</p></content>
        <outtro><p>No, too much bias</p></outtro></knowl>
</knowl>